Greg Simon Ph.D.

gregorygsimon@gmail.com (805) 746-1668

Professional Summary

Expertise in the practice and theory of state-of-the-art data analysis, modern statistics, and machine learning. Demonstrated projects that drive team success in data wrangling, automation, dashboarding, forecasting, machine learning, image recognition, and natural language processing. Team-centered, goal-oriented, and driven to succeed.

Project portfolio available at: https://gregorygsimon.github.io

Education

Ph.D. Mathematics, 2016, University of Michigan

M.S. Data Analytics, expected 2021, Western Governors University

B.A. Mathematics, 2010, University of California, Santa Cruz

• cum laude and highest honors in the major (mathematics)

Technical Skills

Languages: Python [pandas, scikit-learn, matplotlib, keras, pytorch, etc.], SQL, Spark, R, Julia (some)

Other: AWS Cloud, Excel, Google Apps Script, Bash/Linux, Git, Docker, Tableau

Certifications: AWS Certification - Machine Learning Specialty (expires 2023, ID#RX11FD2CEB4E1WKF)

Employment Experience

Western Governors University Course Faculty [2017 – Present]

- Teaching applied statistics outstanding student evaluations available
- Gathering, cleaning, and analyzing data from approx. 1500 active students at any given time
- Led machine learning project aligning course practice problems with positive student outcomes
- Responsible for departments data visualization in Python
- Developed dashboard to automate collection and visualization of student progress and model to predict student success on assessment
- Developed automation pipeline for department to email messages to hundreds of students daily

University of Michigan Graduate Student Instructor [2011-2016], Lecturer [2016-2017]

- Primary instructor for calculus series, including differential equations and multi-variable calculus
- Course coordinator for Accelerated Precalculus (2 terms), Calculus II

Selected Talks and Presentations

Finite Simple Groups: Thirty Years of the Atlas and Beyond, poster session. 11/2015, Princeton. AMS Central Fall Sectional Meeting, Special Session on K-Loops, Near Domains, and Nonassociative Division algebras. 10/2015. Loyola University.

AMS Central Spring Sectional Meeting, Special Session on Groups and Representations, 4/2015. Michigan State University.

Projects and Workshops

Image recognition 6-week project with TrainX 7/2019 – 9/2019

- Co-lead of five student-practitioners developing image recognition model in AWS to predict make and models from images of car from street-facing webcams, in connection with Detroit PD
- Contact: Aubrey Agee, TrainX co-founder, aubrey@trainx.ai

updated: Aug 10, 2020